Business Development –International Sales

Karthikeyan Ravichandran

+919840827298, +919962738765

Karthikice1986@gmail.com

Skype Name: Seekar86

Business Development Executive (Sales & Marketing) / Project Coordinator

A qualified Instrumentation resources person (Bachelor of Instrumentation and Control Engineering) with close to 4 years of experience in Sales & Marketing (M.B.A. – UK); working across industries with a creative flair in Managing Projects, with a long-term objective of creating a balanced career as a Leader as well as a Team Player, initiating the career in Project Management.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Magzter Inc (Sept 2011 till

Present)

Business Development Executive (International Sales & Marketing)

Magzter is a unique global digital mobile magazine store and newsstand that makes it easy for publishers to offer digital editions of their titles, and even easier for readers to enjoy them.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Working closely with the management in developing and implementing business development strategy for the territories assigned.
- Working with the team to achieve short and long term revenue and profit growth.
- Maintain and monitor the business cycle of the project assigned and execute the approved plan.
- Update and maintain customer information database on regular basis using Sales Force CRM tool.
- Giving status update regarding the business prospects to the management and clients, arranging meetings for the same.
- Conduct market research to develop roadmap and sales strategy to secure new business.
- Assisting the clients for Advertising, Social Media Marketing, Promotional programs and tradeshows.

Business Development –International Sales

Reference:

Varun Nagarajan – Business Development Manager

Contact No: +91 9900156677

G.S. Babu & Co. (Leather Tanners and Exporters) (2.5 years)

(June 2007 to Dec

2008 &

Oct 2010 to Sept 2011)

Sales Coordinator

G.S. Babu & Co is a well-known leather tanners and exporters with a strong customer base in Europe and Asia. They are the principle suppliers for brands like Bally and Timberland.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Collecting up-to-date information on the status of orders from various clients and the number of sales attained.
- Creating detailed sales reports to present to the management and potential investors.
- Maintaining good working relations with the existing suppliers and attempting to secure more favourable contract terms for future business.
- Conducting research to identify the best regions to market the key products. This is done through identifying sales trends and product preference across different regions.

Reference:

H. Premanand - Managing Director

Contact No: +91 9443387808

Stratom Consultants, London (PART-TIME)

(Apr 2010 to Aug 2010) & (May 2009 to Oct

2009)

Worked as a part-time employee in the firm during summer breaks to acquire project management skills and worked in two different projects namely;

- Construction of Olympic sports village complex and
- Construction of Environment center of Wales

Business Development –International Sales

Reference:

K.D. Chandirassegarane – Director Contact No: 0044-7900563687

Education

- M.B.A. (Project Management), University of Wales, Cardiff, United Kingdom, (2010) (CGPA 5.0)
- Bachelor of Instrumentation and Control, St. Joseph's college of engineering, Chennai (2007) (61%)
- H.S.C. (Tamil Nadu State board), Montford Matriculation, Chennai (2003) (73%)
- S.S.L.C., Montford Matriculation, Chennai (2001) with (73%)

Academic Projects

Duration: 4 months

Undergraduate Project:

RFID based access control system

Post Graduate Dissertation:

"The Role of Business Process RE-engineering (BPR) in Project management using a comparative Case Study of Leather Industry"

Details: The main objective of the research is to make analysis on the restructuring process in terms of modernization of the industry and implement the key outcomes and results of the research in any company related to the industry.

Personal Details

Father's Name: Ravichandran P.

Nationality: Indian

Date of Birth: 11 June 1986

Languages Known: English, Tamil, French (Level 1)